<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one or more
  contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file distributed with
  this work for additional information regarding copyright ownership.
  The ASF licenses this file to You under the Apache License, Version 2.0
  (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
  the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
-->
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">
<document> 
  <header> 
    <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title> 
  </header> 
  <body> 
    <section id="General">
      <title>General Questions</title>
      <ul>
      	<li><strong>How do I provision a new identity?</strong><br/>
      	    <p>	
	    You can always use the FHoSS web interface running accesible <a href="http://localhost:8080/">http://localhost:8080</a> 
	    on the FHoSS machine (this web-interface is part of the HSS, so you need to run the HSS in order to access it). 
	    If you also want to use the user with the SIP2IMS Gateway, look further <a href="/docs/faq.html#sip2ims">down</a> in the
	    SIP2IMS FAQ.
	    </p>	
	    <p>
	    For automating this process, you can also use the add-imscore-user.sh script found in the ser_ims/cfg/. Look inside
	    for usage instructions.
	    </p>	
      	</li>
      	<li><strong>I want to commit something, but I don't have right access.</strong><br/>
      		In order to keep a high quality for the code, only a limited number of maintainers have modification permissions. Each is 
      		responsible	for checking if new patches work properly and for the administration of the sub-projects. Please post your 
      		patches to the mailing-lists and they will be checked and applied. If you are an active contributor and you demonstrate
      		that your patches can be trusted, we will add you as a project maintainer.
      	</li>
      	<li><strong>OK, but what if I want to make a big change and would require a branch?</strong><br/>
      		Then you will get this access sooner. You will just have to convince one of the maintainers that your branch makes sense.
      	</li>
      	<li><strong>Can I contribute with another IMS component that I am working on?</strong><br/>
      		You are most welcomed. Just let us know and we will import it in the SVN.
      	</li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section id="SVN">
      <title>Subversion</title>
      <ul>
      	<li><strong>I tried the SVN URLs on berliOS but I get an error.</strong><br/>
      		berliOS uses a template for indicating the SVN URLs. As we have more than 1 sub-project, please use the links indicated 
      		<a href="sources/index.html">here</a>.
      	</li>
      	<li><strong>I want to commit something, but I don't have right access.</strong><br/>
      		In order to keep a high quality for the code, only a limited number of maintainers have modification permissions. Each is 
      		responsible	for checking if new patches work properly and for the administration of the sub-projects. Please post your 
      		patches to the mailing-lists and they will be checked and applied. If you are an active contributor and you demonstrate
      		that your patches can be trusted, we will add you as a project maintainer.
      	</li>
      	<li><strong>OK, but what if I want to make a big change and would require a branch?</strong><br/>
      		Then you will get this access sooner. You will just have to convince one of the maintainers that your branch makes sense.
      	</li>
      	<li><strong>Can I contribute with another IMS component that I am working on?</strong><br/>
      		You are most welcomed. Just let us know and we will import it in the SVN.
      	</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section id="CSCFs">
      <title>Call Session Control Functions</title>
      <ul>
      	<li><strong>I get an error that "setkey" is not found when starting the P-CSCF. How do I fix it?</strong><br/>
      		Install the ipsec-tools. "setkey" is included there and it is used to set-up the IPSec Security Associations. Also, don't
      		forget to check if you have IPSec AH and ESP compiled in your kernel.
      	</li>
      	<li><strong>How do I enable the RTP Proxy?</strong><br/>
      		Download and install RTPProxy. You can get it from <a href="http://www.iptel.org/downloads">http://www.iptel.org/downloads</a>.
      		Then start it with the following command line:
      		<source>rtpproxy -l 1.2.3.4 -s udp:127.0.0.1:34999 -f</source>
      		Edit the pcscf.cfg and enable the RTPProxy:
      		<source>modparam("pcscf","rtpproxy_enable", 1)</source>      		
      	</li>
      	<li><strong>Do I really need a DNS server? Won't "/etc/hosts" work?</strong><br/>
      		You really need a DNS server. For example the P-CSCF will do a NAPTR/SRV query to find the I-CSCF and only a 
      		true DNS server will be able to solve this. If you need help with that, please read 
      		<a href="/docs/install.html#annexa">this</a>.
      	</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section id="HSS">
      <title>Home Subscriber Server</title>
      <ul>
      	<li><strong>Can I compile FHoSS without connectivity to Internet?</strong><br/>
			The usual problem that occurs when the additional resources are generated, through ant gen, without a current Intenet connection is: <source> Error reading import file 
			'http://www.w3.org/2001/xml.xsd': java.net.NoRouteToHostException: No route to host.</source> This occurs because the source generator
			tries to import the specified file from the remote address.
			The solution is:
			<ol>
				<li> Download the xml.xsd from here: <a href ="http://www.w3.org/2001/xml.xsd"> xml.xsd </a> and copy it on your machine, for example in <strong>xsd/</strong> folder of FHoSS </li>
				<li> Edit the file xsd/ZhDataType.xsd and change the path 
					 "http://www.w3.org/2001/xml.xsd" to your local path; for example "file:///opt/OpenIMSCore/FHoSS/xsd/xml.xsd" 
					 E.g. Original file:
					<source>
					  &#060;xs:import namespace="http://www.w3.org/XML/1998/namespace"
				       schemaLocation="http://www.w3.org/2001/xml.xsd"/&#062;
					</source>
					Modified file:
					<source>
					  &#060;xs:import namespace="http://www.w3.org/XML/1998/namespace"
				       schemaLocation="file:///opt/OpenIMSCore/FHoSS/xsd/xml.xsd"/&#062;
					</source>
				</li>
				 <li> Run again ant gen and now it will work. </li> 
			</ol>
      	</li>
      </ul>      
    </section>
    <section id="sip2ims">
      <title>SIP-to-IMS Gateway</title>
      <ul>
      	<li><strong>How do I provision a new user?</strong><br/>
      		Use serweb or another tool to create a user in the credentials table. Alternatively, you can manually add a similar
      		entry to those of Alice/Bob. HA1 is irrelevant and can be left blank. HA1b can be computed using e.g.:
      		<source>ser_ims/utils/gen_ha1/gen_ha1 user realm password</source>
      		Don't forget: The username must be the same as the private AND the public identity of the user, as SIP UEs do not usually
      		make a distinction between them. The password must be the same as the secret key provisioned in the HSS. It seems that 
		many users confuse the private identity, so here is a correct example:				
		<source>ser_ims/utils/gen_ha1/gen_ha1 alice@open-ims.test open-ims.test alice</source>
      	</li>
      	<li><strong>It doesn't work with another Proxy-CSCF. Why?</strong><br/>
      		The P-CSCF assumes that it is the first hop for any UE originated requests. Unfortunately now the SIP-to-IMS Gateway
      		works in proxy mode and our P-CSCF is hacked to recognize this case. There are plans to move to a full B2BUA mode, but
      		this will take some time.
      	</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section id="ue">
      <title>User Endpoints</title>
      <ul>
      	<li><strong>Is there a free IMS Client?</strong><br/>
      		Unfortunately we don't know of any. Our OpenIC is available only commercially 
      	(Contact: <a href="mailto:info@open-ims.org?subject=OpenIC%20request">info@open-ims.org</a>).</li>
      	<li><strong>Then how can one test the core?</strong><br/>
      		We are sharing also the SIP-to-IMS Gateway and you could use a SIP client. Or use 
      	<a href="http://sipp.sourceforge.net/">SIPp</a>, which has support even for AKA and media</li>
      	<li><strong>I am using SIP client X and it does not work. What could be wrong?</strong><br/>
      		We know that for example 
      		<a href="http://www.gnomemeeting.org/">Ekiga</a> does not comply with the Digest authentication RFC and is unusable. Some
      		other clients might have problems. Please let us know if you encounter such a case so that we could either solve the issue
      		or post it here. Before you do that, please check that you have configured in correctly as indicated 
      		<a href="/docs/install.html#step7">here</a>.
      	</li>      	
      </ul>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
