<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  Copyright 2002-2004 The Apache Software Foundation or its licensors,
  as applicable.

  Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  You may obtain a copy of the License at

      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
-->
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">
<document> 
  <header> 
    <title>Welcome to Open IMS Core</title> 
  </header> 
  <body> 
    <section id="welcome">
      <title>Welcome to Open IMS Core's Homepage</title>
      <p>So you have found us! Good!</p>      
    </section>

    <section id="disclaimer">
      <title>Mandatory disclaimer, before any usage</title>
      <p>
		It has to be noted that this  <strong>  Open Source IMS Core 
		System is not intended to become or act as a product in a commercial context!  </strong>
		Its sole purpose is to provide an IMS core reference implementation for
		IMS technology testing and IMS application prototyping for research
		purposes, typically performed in IMS test-beds.
	  </p>
	  <p>
		Users of the Open Source IMS Core System have to be aware that IMS
		technology may be subject of patents and licence terms, as being
		specified within the various IMS-related IETF, ITU-T, ETSI, and 3GPP
		standards. Thus all Open IMS Core users have to take notice of this
		fact and have to agree to check out carefully before installing, using
		and extending the Open Source IMS Core System, if related patents and
		licences may become applicable to the intended usage context.
	  </p>
    </section>

    <section id="license">
		<title>General Public License v2</title>
		<p>
			Copyright (C) 2004-2006 FhG Fokus
		</p>
		<p>
			The Open IMS Core is an open source IMS CSCFs &amp; HSS implementation.
		</p>
		<p>
			Open IMS Core is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify
			it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
			the Free Software Foundation; either version 2 of the License, or (at
			your option) any later version.
		</p>
		<p>
			For a license to use the Open IMS Core software under conditions other
			than those described here, or to purchase support for this software,
			please contact Fraunhofer FOKUS by e-mail at the following addresses: 
			<a href="mailto:info@open-ims.org">info@open-ims.org</a>
		</p>
		<p>
			Open IMS Core is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but
			WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
			MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU
			General Public License for more details.
		</p>
		<p>
			You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License along
			with this program; if not, write to the Free Software Foundation, Inc.,
			59 Temple Place, Suite 330, Boston, MA 02111-1307 USA 
		</p> 
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
